Romeo Martinez

Contact | romesmartinez@gmail.com 240.620.5942

I am a multidisciplinary designer, with a focus on product design, brand design, illutration and web design. Currently working out of Bethesda, Maryland as the design lead at Employee Navigator. I'm a passionate designer with a mind for solving challenging problems and an eye for creating beautiful products, solutions and experiences. For more infomation, please contact.

Experience

Employee Navigator from May 2016 - Current PRODUCT DESIGN/LEAD DESIGN

As the company sole designer, I am responsible for all visual and design decisions as well as the UX & UI on new & existing product features. I lead the creation of prototypes & collaborate closely with developers, product managers, & QA to accomplish various product milestones. I've also overseen and been responsible for project management on various project sprints.

I am also responsible for all brand & marketing design needs(e-mail, blog, social media, branding), and video & animation needs. I've also provided and lead the art/creative direction for our annual EN users conference since 2016.

Major projects include:

- Public facing web design
- Employee Application UX redesign
- Marketplace of Plans UX/UI
- EN Users Conference 2016-2019
- Vendor Portal UX/UI
- PTO weekends & variable hour UX/UI

Education

BFA In Graphic Design The Art Institute of Washington Rosslyn, VA

Liberal Arts Associate Degree Montgomery College Germantown, MD

Certificates

UX Design Certificate General Assembly Washington D.C.

O'keefe Communications from February 2016 - April 2016 FREELANCE VISUAL DESIGNER

Full Time contract freelancer, responsible for executing major conference keynote presentations and accompanying graphics. Responsible for producing, developing, and creating promotional video visuals and themes for client campaign use.

EventKloud From September 2014 - December 2015 UI UX DESIGNER & BRAND DESIGN

Serving as the lead designer in charge of managing company brand & Identity. Involved in the web design for EventKloud website, UX/UI design of their SaaS platform, mobile app designs and additional event site designs. Responsible for all company visual design(blog, web ad content, graphics, etc), and additional collateral for conferences/ expos.

GKA Advertising from November 2015 - December 2015 FREELANCE GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Rockville, MD. Working with the in-house design time at GKA and responsible for creating/editing promotional print material(brochures, flyers, catalogs), developing logo and branding identities, web graphics, and illustrating housing blueprint.

TrackMaven from June 2014 - September 2014 **DESIGN INTERN**

Washington D.C. Responsible for blog graphics illustrations & visuals, speaker keynote presentations, web ad design, layout design & print design for expos.

Earlier roles can be found on my linkedin

Tools

Sketch Invision Invision Studio Adobe Creative Suite HTML & CSS & Javascript Microsoft Visual Studio Atom Text Editor GitHub & GitLab Powerpoint Keynote

Knowledge

User Interface Design Human Centered Design Visualization of Userflows **Project Managment** Wireframing Pattern & Brand Standard Guides Web Usability Research on User Experience Good Sense for Typography Color Theory Knowledge